Rubén D. Pire

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

rubenpire7@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer and React enthusiast with a passion for clean and easy-to-follow code. Experienced in pair programming and remote working. Fluent in several languages, frameworks, and technologies, and a team player with an optimistic personality that can boost the morale of any team.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, SASS

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Work, Pair-Programming, Teamwork

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

July, 2021 - Present

OLC Re-opening Website — Re-opening website for Obelisk Language Center a Venezuelan academy of languages.

Built with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Math Magicians — A project built as part of the Microverse program implementing the React framework.

Built with: JavaScript, React

<u>Covid Metrics</u> — A website that implemented SPA dynamics. It displays statistics and information related to the COVID-19 pandemic for regions in the United Kingdom. Information is taken from an API.

• Built with: HTML5, CSS3, Webpack

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

October, 2021 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

July, 2021 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.
- Won the "Collaborator of the Month" award.

UNEXPO

November, 2011 - December, 2018

Engineering, Electricity

- One semester of programming logic and algorithms.
- Coursework about PLC programming.
- Worked as a preparator for the signature "Electrical Power Systems I". Providing auxiliary classes, assistance, and project reviews for other students.